www.aaronrobson.uk mobile: 07411 863293

https://github.com/aaronrobson

Personal Statement

I consider myself to be an organised software developer. I do my utmost to keep up with developments in the field, new techniques, libraries and languages; in order to make more informed decisions. To keep on top of open issues I log them with detailed reproduction steps, so that myself and my colleagues can hit the ground running in resolving them.

My professional programming experience is primarily in Delphi, C# and SQL. I have used Python and Haskell heavily outside of work and I have experimented with Scheme Lisp and Prolog. I have worked on several personal projects including an implementation of John Conway's Game of Life and a numeric base converter.

I have recently been learning Django from a friend and ex-colleague and while I am by no means an expert at this stage I feel confident with working with models and some basic views.

As much as I enjoy programming I am a social person who enjoys catching up with my colleagues over a meal out. Outside of work I like going on cruises and cycling holidays.

Professional Development

I have earned a Professional Scrum Developer I certificate, see scrum.org/user/282980 and appendix.

Attended the SDD 2017 conference.

Employment

Wheatley Solutions Ltd.

2016-Present

Developer

Bacton, Suffolk

Working with Delphi, C# and Oracle PL/SQL database projects. Assisted members of QA in producing test data generation scripts in Python for the purpose of automated testing.

I feel it is important to push for process improvements, I have been included in a steering group for the Jenkins build server and as part of work on continuous deployment I have been tasked with automating the process of packaging releases and writing release notes.

Digi Europe Ltd.

2010 – 2016

Software Engineer

Haverhill, Suffolk

Developing and maintaining current software whilst building bespoke solutions for weighing and labelling machines.

The position included controlling and collection of running information from in-house (and partner's) machinery via APIs from client applications and services. I developed a simple Android application in Java to select products on the in house machines for demonstration purposes.

Vast experience of meeting customers to discuss future development projects and visiting customer's sites for software maintenance.

I have developed some in-house utilities to improve my own work-flow and to help the development team, these include a log file analyser written in Python and a label format converter from a legacy third party binary format to a new XML representation written in Haskell and designed to be compatible with the newer revision of the flagship product as an upgrade path for customers.

Education University of Lincoln

2007-2010

Software Engineering B.Sc.

Lincolnshire

During my time at University I had the opportunity within a team to build a web based holiday booking system. I also built a blog based on the principles of CRUD.

In the Mobile and Distributed Computing unit I learnt a lot by the challenge of developing a C# chat program.

Hills Road Sixth Form College

2005-2007

College

Cambridge

A-Levels in Computing, Maths and Chemistry (grades B, C and D respectfully). AS-Levels in Physics and Critical Thinking.

Witchford Village College

2002 - 2005

Secondary School

Ely, Cambs

Nine GCSEs grade C and above, including an A* in Maths and an A in both Science and English.

Technical

Books I have enjoyed reading:

Reading

Brain of the Firm, The Mythical Man-Month, The Pragmatic Programmer, Design of Everyday Things by Don Norman, Surely You're Joking Mr Feynman, Peopleware, Slack, The Design of Everyday Things, Paul Graham and Dijkstra's essays.

References

Available upon request.

This is to certify that on Tue 3 Oct 2017

Aaron Robson

demonstrated a fundamental understanding of professional software development using Scrum. This includes building increments of done, potentially releasable product; applying contemporary software engineering practices and tooling; and working as part of a self-organizing, cross-functional team – using the Scrum framework.

In recognition of this, Scrum.org is pleased to provide this certification.



Professional Scrum Developer I



Ken Schwaler



CERTIFICATE OF ACHIEVEMENT

Aaron Robson

has successfully completed

Professional Scrum Developer (.NET)

Granted by QA Ltd on 08 September 2017

William John



